Ruth Panashe Kaseke, Computer Engineering Student

+263713670490, ruthpanash@gmail.com

PROFILE

Knowledgeable, performance and detail-oriented Computer Engineering student who excels at configuring and maintaining hardware and software and handling technical support requests. Possesses great technological expertise, well-developed communication skills and ability to perform well in a team.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Aug 2022 — Aug 2023

IT intern, Bindura Nickel Corporation

Bindura

- Enhanced onboarding efficiency for new employees by documenting IT processes and procedures.
- Achieved a 15% improvement in IT support response time by implementing IT helpdesk systems and tools.
- Ensured optimal software and hardware performance by installing, configuring, and maintaining them.
- Resolved hardware and software issues effectively, providing crucial technical support to end users.
- Delivered impactful data insights through the development of visualizations and reports.
- Safeguarded data integrity by performing regular system backups.
- Improved cybersecurity awareness by training users on cybersecurity ethics.

Feb 2021 — Present

Remote Intern, Paragon Tech

Remote

- · Ensured timely and budget-compliant virtual meetings for remote teams through effective coordination.
- Enhanced processes and generated innovative ideas by researching new technologies and trends in the
 cybersecurity industry.
- Advanced research and career development skills by engaging with mentors.
- Strengthened knowledge and expertise through online cybersecurity training.

EDUCATION

Oct 2020 — Present

BSc Honours in Computer Engineering, University of Zimbabwe

Feb 2018 — Nov 2019

A Level Certificate, Kriste Mambo Girls High School

2As, 2Bs

Feb 2014 — Nov 2017

O Level Certificate, Kriste Mambo Girls High School

12As ZIMSEC, 2 Distinctions HEXCO

SKILLS

Critical thinking and problem

solving

Time Management

Fast Learner

Adaptability

Project Management

Programming in Python

Mobile App development

Generative AI

PROJECTS

University of Zimbabwe

Harare

- Played a key role in creating an inventory system in C#, significantly improving efficiency in stock taking, user management, and trail auditing, leading to streamlined operations.
- Contributed to the successful development of a Smart Access Control and Monitoring system, enhancing security and monitoring capabilities for the organization.
- Completed an internship project by developing a biometric-based Miners Check-in System, which increased accuracy and security in tracking miner attendance.
- Created an innovative mobile self-checkout solution utilizing Mask RCNN and Atrous Convolution, revolutionizing the checkout process and reducing wait times for customers.

Bindura Nickel Corporation

Bindura

- Created a web-based internal directory, enhancing accessibility and organization of employee information.
- Played a vital role in the seamless migration and installation from Ellipse ERP to SAP, ensuring minimal disruption and increased efficiency.
- Developed a biometric-based Miners Check-in System, significantly improving attendance accuracy and security.
- Improved cybersecurity awareness and compliance by facilitating users in the KnowBe4 cybersecurity training.

CERTIFICATIONS

Cybersecurity Essentials , Cisco

Predictive Project Management Essentials, PMI

Project Management Foundations, LinkedIn

Career Essentials in Generative AI, Microsoft and LinkedIn

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Media Manager, Give a Hand Charity Club

2nd Vice President, Hack the Box UZ

Member, ShiftKey UZ

Member, UoZ Technovators Society

Member, GDSC UZ

REFERENCES

Addlight Mukwazvure from University of Zimbabwe

amukwazvure@ceic.uz.ac.zw · +263 715 087 995

Thomas Lusiyano from Bindura Nickel Corporation

tlusiyano@bnc.co.zw · +263 772 584 581